<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs on ⭐️ The Great SummerEmacs Blog ⭐️</title>
    <link>https://summeremacs.github.io/tags/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emacs on ⭐️ The Great SummerEmacs Blog ⭐️</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 13:28:31 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://summeremacs.github.io/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zeus and Prot</title>
      <link>https://summeremacs.github.io/posts/zeus-and-prot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 13:28:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://summeremacs.github.io/posts/zeus-and-prot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
After coming home, I started reviewing Prot&amp;#39;s progress with the hut this morning. I saw his video post about a pomegranate tree which had mysteriously sprouted. Also, I saw him working like crazy to build this hut. So, after putting some odd links together in my head, I came up with the following screenplay. 🙃 I wrote this really fast so I hope it comes across as okay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Emacs With Tramp</title>
      <link>https://summeremacs.github.io/posts/using-emacs-with-tramp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 12:24:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://summeremacs.github.io/posts/using-emacs-with-tramp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;headline-1&#34;&gt;
All my server stuff in Emacs
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I wanted to tidy up some stuff on my server. I had a ton of photos and videos I wanted to organize on my servers. Also, it was getting a little messy with my old way of doing the directories because I had set it up before I had learned how to do most of the things that I know how to do. You see, I have a main drive on my main server, and then a backup drive off of it. But it was a bit messy. I&amp;#39;d dump stuff in one directory as a temp storage place at the root of that directory, but I never did the &lt;code class=&#34;verbatim&#34;&gt;--delete&lt;/code&gt; flags for &lt;code class=&#34;verbatim&#34;&gt;rsync&lt;/code&gt; which meant that I&amp;#39;d have to, every now and then, go into my backup drive and just delete all the trash by hand. I never had the time to fix that. I only learned a few things about rsync when I had set it up and even though I set up another rsync with the &lt;code class=&#34;verbatim&#34;&gt;--delete&lt;/code&gt; flag, I never had the time to do a &lt;code class=&#34;verbatim&#34;&gt;--dry-run&lt;/code&gt; on the important stuff I wanted to update. I&amp;#39;d never use a flag like that without doing a dry run. Ever.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Came to Use Emacs and Other Things</title>
      <link>https://summeremacs.github.io/posts/how-i-came-to-use-emacs-and-other-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 18:01:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://summeremacs.github.io/posts/how-i-came-to-use-emacs-and-other-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;headline-1&#34;&gt;
This is the story of how I came to use Emacs and other things
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m tired of repeating myself so I&amp;#39;m writing this down so I don&amp;#39;t have to. You&amp;#39;re probably only here if you asked me how I came to learn about Emacs and the CLI and other things. Well, this is the story:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Use Emacs</title>
      <link>https://summeremacs.github.io/posts/how-i-use-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 12:06:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://summeremacs.github.io/posts/how-i-use-emacs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://summeremacs.github.io/img/pink-emacs-icon.png&#34; alt=&#34;/img/pink-emacs-icon.png&#34; title=&#34;/img/pink-emacs-icon.png&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;/&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
Emacs in Pink is your Friend.
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;headline-1&#34;&gt;
An explanation of how I use Emacs
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#39;m honoured that you all have invited me to share my thoughts, and I especially appreciate the $50,000 advanced speakers&amp;#39; fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of people have asked me to write down how I use Emacs because they&amp;#39;re curious how I use it every day since about a year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First thing you should know: I&amp;#39;m not a programmer. I&amp;#39;m mostly a personal assistant and researcher, as well as a few other things. So my primary use for Emacs is a central point for information gathering, linking, and organising big and small projects. However, I&amp;#39;m not a stranger to the terminal, or git, or a few other things like that (like rsync for example).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#39;m going to explain my setup on the hardware and software side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-2&#34; class=&#34;outline-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;headline-2&#34;&gt;
The Hardware Setup:
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-2&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use all iOS and Mac devices (as does my boss, gf, and bffs/roomies).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do have a Raspberry Pi and Mint Linux server in my home office. My boss said I can buy something way better and beefier but I like my little servers the way they are. They&amp;#39;re sorta proof that I have some geek-cred. 🙃&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My Mac/iOS devices are all automatically synced to iCloud so all my notes and files are available on all of my devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I run Syncthing to sync my files to my Raspberry Pi automatically. I have an rsync script running every night to mirror the two main drives of my NAS to my mirror backup drives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-3&#34; class=&#34;outline-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;headline-3&#34;&gt;
The Software Setup
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-3&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-4&#34; class=&#34;outline-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;headline-4&#34;&gt;
The folders/directories:
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-4&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-5&#34; class=&#34;outline-4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;headline-5&#34;&gt;
Everything I need is in &lt;code class=&#34;verbatim&#34;&gt;~/Documents/sync&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-5&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because &lt;code class=&#34;verbatim&#34;&gt;~/Documents&lt;/code&gt; is automatically synced to iCloud without me ever having to touch anything, everything in it is mirrored to all of my devices. From there, I have a folder inside called sync. So ~/Documents/sync which is the folder where all of my org files, notes, etc are located. This folder is automatically synced to my Raspberry Pi with Syncthing every few seconds. And that gets backed up every night to my mirror drives on my Raspberry Pi. Also, since ~/Documents is automatically backed up with Time Machine on my server as well, I have a second backup (also backed up to the mirror drives at night). This way, I have more than one independent backup going at all times so I shouldn&amp;#39;t (ideally) ever lose my files. And I have access to all notes and files on all of my iOS devices at all times as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
